NARRATOR: They call him "the rock."
MAN: Welcome to Alcatraz.
NARRATOR: A hell of steel and cement for the
worst of the worst.
GEORGIA: There were dangerous men.
You had to be alert all the time.
NARRATOR: But the waters surrounding it could be
even more dangerous.
The guards warned the inmates that they were infested with
sharks in search of fugitive prey.
A new sighting to
meters of the island could reveal that it was true.
SCOTT: That bite changed.
Everything we knew about great white sharks and science
from San Francisco Bay.
NARRATOR: What did the prisoners face when they swam?
along the coast of Sharkatraz?
The Island of Alcatraz
one of the points
most famous geographical landmarks in the San Francisco Bay.
Home of some
of the most infamous criminals in history.
But the water surrounding the island belongs to another
predator class
sharks.
DOUGLAS: There are between 12 and 15 different species
of sharks...
half of them live here full time.
The other half are visitors entering and leaving the bay.
NARRATOR: Scientists have claimed for decades that
the shark that has the worst reputation,
the great white shark,
does not hunt in the bay in which the island is located.
But they are about to change their minds.
It's a sunny day in October 2015.
Hundreds of visitors come to see Alcatraz
They are witnesses of something that no one believed was possible
less than 10 meters from the island.
BOY: It's a great white shark.
WOMAN: Oh. My God.
NARRATOR: A shark
white attacks and devours a California sea lion.
Look ooo...
BOY: Dad takes a picture.
WOMAN: Lucky we're not on the boat.
BOY: It's down there. I can't believe it.
NARRATOR: This incredible event never seen before
shocks scientists.
The area outside the
bay, known as "the red triangle",
It is feared because there are white sharks.
They come here to feed on seals and sea lions.
From August to October is when their number is greatest,
but this is the first time in history that someone has seen
a white shark feeding inside
San Francisco Bay.
DOUGLAS: Since 1880
no great white sharks were seen in the bay.
It was always assumed that they did not enter the bay.
Why they didn't enter the bay? One could only speculate.
The video shows
a predatory behavior typical of a white shark.
What surprises us most is that it hasn't happened before.
NARRATOR: Oceanography experts, like the explorer
submarine Scott Cassell,
They think this changes everything.
SCOTT: Here a few meters from the island
the white shark ate the sea lion.
That bite changed everything we knew about sharks.
whites and the science of the San Francisco Bay.
This is where it happened right here. CHILD: He's going to eat it.
Look, there is the heart.
NARRATOR: The sighting
revives the old fear that there are dangerous sharks in the bay
in search of easy prey.
A fear that once
prevented prisoners at Alcatraz from attempting to escape.
SCOTT: Imagine for a moment that you are a prisoner watching
through the window the beautiful sunny day.
You're looking at an adorable seal and suddenly,
sees a giant white shark attacking her
and kills her in the middle of a mass of bloody foam.
It wouldn't take away their desire to escape.
I would take them off.
WOMAN: Oh. My God. I hate this place.
NARRATOR: In this prison
islander, no prisoner escaped the legend of Sharkatraz.
The guards made sure that the prisoners thought
than diving into the water
It was a death sentence.
TOM: Since the day that
arrived, the word was spread among the prisoners
and the officers that if
escaped from prison and were going to be eaten by sharks.
We believed it. I believed it, everyone believed it.
The most powerful psychological weapon they had
prison authorities
It was the threat of being devoured
in the waters of Alcatraz Bay by sharks
that passed under the Golden Gate Bridge.
NARRATOR: The guards took out
They took advantage of the rumors and told stories about sharks.
trained patrollers
the island and a particularly ferocious giant
the one they called Bruce.
BILL: One of the guards told the prisoners that they had
caught a shark in the bay.
It had turned out to be a white one.
They cut off one of his fins to
that I could only swim in circles in these waters.
PHILIP: We fed the
idea that there were sharks in the bay and there were.
Many inmates pointed them out to me. They said: "Captain, look
"There's a fin sticking out of the water."
NARRATOR: But not everyone.
The stories of sea monsters were frightening.
Alcatraz prisoners were
the worst of the worst, the most fearsome of the fearsome.
MAN: 105, 107 bars.
NARRATOR: They couldn't control them in any other prison.
MAN: Ready. Lock them up.
BILL: Soy Bill Baker,
prisoner 1259 AZ former Alcatraz prisoner.
He had escaped from other prisons.
We were in the cell most of the time. That
It was the worst.
NARRATOR: The strict rules
created to control them made many prisoners desperate
to escape.
BILL: It was always clear to me that knowing that you weren't going to
escaping with time drove you crazy.
NARRATOR: In his
29 years of history as a federal penitentiary
The prisoners attempted to escape from Alcatraz 14 times.
Most were caught or killed.
but on 6 occasions,
The desperate prisoners dived into the bay
and swam in waters that
They believed they were full of hungry sharks.
The first to escape were Theodore Cole and Ralph Roe.
December 1937.
After two years on the Rock, Cole and Roe had had enough.
For them, the fascination for
Freedom far outweighs any fear of sharks.
MAN: I don't want to spend my life here.
BILL: They had long sentences and wanted to be free. So simple.
like that.
MAN: I'd rather risk spending one more day on this rock.
NARRATOR: But escape from
Alcatraz without a boat in the middle of winter is almost impossible.
The fear of the prisoners
sharks are just ONE of the obstacles.
To swim to shore, Coe and Roe will have to battle it out.
water temperatures
dangerously low below 10 degrees...
already powerful currents
that will drag them out to the open sea.
MAN: Let's find a way out through those bars.
NARRATOR: They are determined and believe they have found a way out.
The two worked in the north wing of the cell block,
in the model industries building.
Inside, they found a
window hidden from the watchful eyes of the guards.
Day after day, they sawed the
bars in secret until they were so thin
that it was easy to break them.
They covered their dedicated work with shoe polish and grease.
Until one day in December
With a lot of fog the prisoners set out to demonstrate
that no prison is escape-proof.
When the guard withdrew to supervise other areas
nearby work
Cole and Roe set to work on their escape.
They quickly reached the fence that borders the coast
and broke the lock.
They were free or so they thought.
They were carrying gas canisters that they had stolen from the building.
model industries to be able to float.
They dived into the icy bay.
And they disappeared.
They were never seen again.
Nobody knows what happened,
but almost everyone believes that Cole and Roe drowned.
SCOTT: At 10 degrees Celsius you can die in a matter of minutes.
hours.
There is very little time to avoid risk.
NARRATOR: In addition to the ice creams
waters, a dense fog covers San Francisco during the months
of winter.
That particular day, the fog was so dense that it was dangerous
even going out to look for them by boat.
Disoriented by the fog dragged by the powerful
currents
the most feasible thing is
that the fugitives never reached the coast.
But some even the prisoners who remained
on the rock they wonder
Could they have been eaten by sharks?
There are almost a dozen of
species of sharks living in the bay.
They are found in all sizes and shapes.
from the deep-feeding leopard shark,
to the intimidatingly large basking sharks.
Despite their gigantic size, sharks
Pilgrims do not hunt mammals.
They feed by filtering water with their gills.
But there is a shark that
It is usually in the bay and could be dangerous
short-snouted cow shark.
DOUGLAS: Cow sharks can grow up to
4 meters.
Adults are known to hunt seals and sea lions.
They are known to form groups
semi-socials who apparently hunt in packs.
But to date it is not known
recorded no attacks by a cow shark on a human.
They are more scavengers than predators.
NARRATOR: In fact, none of the shark species
that prowl the bay
from San Francisco has attacked a human.
Except one, the white shark.
DOUGLAS: They are sharks that weigh 1500 kilos and have
a bite radius of 50 centimeters.
They can cut a California sea lion in half.
They can gut an adult elephant seal.
And, once it's dead, bite it to your heart's content.
NARRATOR: They evolved over millions of years.
and became excellent predators.
Their sharp teeth are constantly renewed.
They have sensory organs
specialized, called ampullae of Lorenzini,
that detect the electrical impulses of their prey.
And a lethal strategy, the violent attack from below.
Once the white shark chose its prey
your target is in grave danger.
SCOTT: If you're in the water with a great white shark
He will see you and you will never see him.
NARRATOR: Although great white sharks are almost
They never attack people
when it happens, it's terrifying.
In 1959, a shocking encounter
confirmed all the stories the guards told
to the prisoners about the killer sharks.
It took place just 6 kilometers from the rock.
It was a brutal attack
where you least expected it.
May 1959.
San Francisco, California.
It's a hot, sunny afternoon at Baker Beach, a beautiful
expanse of sand
a few meters from the bay
less than a kilometer
and a half southwest of the Golden Gate Bridge.
Shirley O'Neill y Albert
Kogler were two 18-year-old college students
who had come to
relax after a long week of classes.
The couple dives into the refreshing waters.
The day couldn't be more perfect.
But everything is about to change.
They pass the first breaker
in search of deeper, calmer waters.
As Albert looks towards the horizon,
Shirley sees a giant shadow pass by a few meters from her
surface
which is heading straight for him.
The water comes to a boil.
It is a gigantic shark almost 5 meters long that buries
his teeth in Albert's flesh.
(shouting)
Shirley's instincts tell her to swim towards the shore.
But he can't let Albert die.
The shark bites him again and she goes back to save him.
He takes him by the torso and, gathering all his strength,
drags him to the shore.
(shouting)
But it's too late.
Albert's arm is almost separated from his shoulder.
He faints.
SHIRLEY: ¡Albert!
NARRATOR: Only two hours
Later, Albert Kogler dies from his serious injuries.
(cries)
The deadly attack
at the mouth of the bay it shocks and terrifies the people.
SCOTT: Albert Kogler died after
being attacked by a great white shark at Baker Beach.
Look over there and look
back and you'll see how close we are to Alcatraz.
NARRATOR: However, and despite
proximity, for decades many shark experts
They believed that this kind of attack could never take place in the
waters surrounding the rock.
Why? Because the bay is
brackish: has a mixture of salty ocean water,
that reaches below the
Golden Gate Bridge at high tide, and fresh water,
that reaches the bay of rivers.
It is known that water
brackish is not the habitat of ocean predators,
like white sharks.
DOUGLAS: What if the
Great white sharks will swim in the brackish water of the bay,
a mixture of salt and fresh water?
They are used to an environment
much saltier seawater and therefore its capacity would be reduced
reaction, their
sensory structures would not function as well,
would decrease their ability to swim, their organs
would fail or even suffer
decompensations that would eventually cause their death.
Physiologically, they would not tolerate being in a low-saline environment.
NARRATOR: But in 2007 and 2008,
while conducting a study at Stanford University
on the migration of white sharks, the sensors
They recorded that there was
5 adult great white sharks
crossing under the Golden Gate Bridge.
Although they had evidence that sharks sometimes
whites entered the bay,
Until recently, most experts believed that
waters were too turbid
so that the white sharks could hunt.
The tides carry algae and sediments and the visibility in
The bay is usually less than one meter.
BOY: It's a great white shark!
NARRATOR: But the recent
A great white shark attack on Alcatraz could indicate
that the waters are different from what was once believed.
WOMAN: My God.
(music)
NARRATOR: To find out, the
Explorer Scott Cassell prepares to dive
in the bay near Alcatraz
to see with your own eyes what the condition of the water is.
SCOTT: This is the submersible for tracking great white sharks.
It has a platform on
in which we can place different systems.
You can explore, investigate, travel great distances.
It is designed like a van that goes underwater.
We can tie it up and it will also be tied to the submersible.
NARRATOR: Scott was a military diver for 15 years and has more than
13 thousand hours of diving experience.
SCOTT: Wait while I put the counterweight on and you'll see what's there.
NARRATOR: Cassell knows what to expect underwater.
He takes his submarine by
the whole world to explore the planet's oceans.
Now you will use it to discover what changed beneath the surface of
the bay that can explain
the recent shark attack.
SCOTT: There's air in two places. Do you want to check it?
WOMAN: Sound check.
SCOTT: Surface, Surface, do you copy?
WOMAN: Perfectly.
SCOTT: Is everyone ready?
NARRATOR: But diving into the waters near Alcatraz.
SCOTT: There's a very strong current.
He's dragging me. He's a danger.
NARRATOR: I might have a few surprises in store for you.
Scientists always
They believed that great white sharks could not hunt
in the murky waters of the bay due to low visibility.
But this new sighting raises new questions.
Scott went in search of answers.
It is a dangerous undertaking.
SCOTT: Is everyone ready? Down, down, down.
Attention, there is a very strong current.
He's dragging me. He's a danger.
I'll go to a shallower area to maintain my position.
WOMAN: Understood.
NARRATOR: By stabilizing
Scott takes a first look at the submersible.
SCOTT: I can see the bottom from the surface. It's 6 meters away from me.
I can't believe it.
NARRATOR: The bay environment is not what he expected.
SCOTT: I can't believe the San Francisco Bay
is so pristine.
It's amazing.
What is happening right now is that it is
entering the tide.
So there is clean ocean water entering the bay.
That explains the visibility.
But I didn't expect it to be so
good. The water is clear.
NARRATOR: Historically,
Visibility in the bay was one meter or less.
Scott estimates he can now see about 6 meters, which
turns it into a hunting ground
much more suitable for marine predators,
like white sharks.
SCOTT: Surface, surface, requesting permission to board.
WOMAN: You're going to get out of the water, aren't you?
SCOTT: Yes, ma'am. We'll let the submersible rest.
Visibility was surprisingly good.
A predator that is
orients by sight, like white sharks,
can locate
easily to a surface prey,
and attack her before she sees it coming.
NARRATOR: A possible
explanation of the amazing transparency of the waters
of the bay may be related to the weather.
There is a relationship between salinity and visibility.
When the waters of a river flow into the bay, the
salinity is higher
and the concentration of silt is lower.
This makes the water more crystalline.
Dry weather often increases visibility in the bay.
DOUGLAS: It's part of the natural cycle
salinity increases and decreases between seasons.
But it's been a while
that, due to the drought in California,
Less fresh water reaches San Francisco Bay in the long term
Francisco.
This caused the increase in
salinity and that it was very similar to that of the ocean.
NARRATOR: Another possible explanation for the increase in
visibility is the tide.
The salinity and transparency of the bay's waters change
constantly due to the tides.
When the waters
oceanic enter, transparency increases.
If we think about the prisoners who tried to escape from Alcatraz,
the exact moment of his attempt
escape would have significantly modified its
odds of facing each other
to a white shark.
In fact, one of the most famous and ingenious escapes shows or
important that it was the time
to survive in the waters near Alcatraz.
May 1962.
Frank Morris, a man
whose record says that his profession was escapology,
He resisted being locked in a cage.
He has good friends on the rock.
His companions Clarence and John Anglin also want to escape.
The stories of Cole and Roe's escape, more than 20 years ago
years, they convince them
that it is not impossible to escape from the rock.
BILL: Frank Morris spent a
a year and a half planning and carrying out the escape.
MAN: Will we be on time? -We have a month. We'll be
ready.
-Okay. Very good. BILL: It was very complicated.
They had to get a lot of materials.
They had to do a lot of things to achieve it.
NARRATOR: The men noticed
that the plumbing conduit located behind the walls
cement of his cell led to a ventilation channel
located on the roof of his cell block.
Night after night, using
Sharp spoons, silently scraped the cement surrounding
a grate located at the back of his cell.
Meanwhile, they made fake heads with cloth and soap oars.
with stolen wood
and inflatable boats with prison raincoats.
They hoped that these makeshift boats would keep them safe.
float and out of reach
of some shark that they could
find by diving into the icy bay.
Then on the night of June 11th
Sometime after 9:30 the escape began.
They placed their heads under the blankets
They entered the pipe conduit and headed
towards freedom.
Once outside, they opened
I speed through the shadows with their boats,
their life preservers and their improvised oars.
They escaped from the island.
But if the time is not right, the powerful
currents could drag them away
towards the open sea.
Towards the red triangle
the dangerous hunting ground of white sharks.
June 1962.
On Alcatraz Island, Frank Morris and the Clarence brothers
and John Anglin have heard
rumors about the escape of prisoners Theodore Cole and
Ralph Roe 25 years ago.
Nobody knows what happened to Cole and Roe, but they didn't have many
chances of survival.
MAN: I got hair from the barbershop.
NARRATOR: But Morris and the Anglins are still convinced.
that it is worth running
those risks in order to achieve freedom.
After months of preparation,
The men finally put their plan into practice.
MAN: Let's hurry. NARRATOR: And they reached the water.
In the midst of the shadows, they row with all their might.
They immediately feel how the powerful currents
they drag them.
And suddenly they disappear.
The next morning. MAN: Anglin! Wake up.
you don't delay everyone.
NARRATOR: The guards find the heads.
fake. MAN: Hey.
NARRATOR: And they sound the alarms.
But after an intense search,
The authorities only found the improvised objects.
by the prisoners to escape against the rocks.
Did they manage to escape?
Did they drown?
Or were they eaten by sharks?
Some believe that Morris and
the Anglin brothers, for using boats to float on water,
were more likely to
reach the coast alive than the previous fugitives.
The mystery remains unsolved.
The only way to know if Morris and the Anglins succeeded
reach the coast
is knowing exactly what time they entered the water.
The strong tides of the bay change drastically
throughout the day.
Using all available information
on the tides,
a team of scientists
Dutch created a digital model of the currents
that there was on the night of the great escape.
DOUGLAS: If we look at the bay of
San Francisco, we see in the middle a separation that we call
Golden Gate.
It is the only area through which water enters and leaves the bay.
If we look at its size we will see that it is gigantic.
There is a large amount of water that during low tide has
to go through that small gap
Consequently, the flow of water accelerates
and generates extremely strong currents in the bay.
It's a complicated environment, it's a dangerous environment.
NARRATOR: This animation shows that if they came out between
9:30 and midnight
The strong current towards the bridge would have swept them away
directly towards the red triangle.
In this region, located
crossing the Golden Gate, from Bodega Bay to Big Sur
and up to the Farallon Islands, there are many marine mammals.
It is the hunting ground of the hated great white sharks.
It is known that there are many shark attacks in this area.
DOUGLAS: The red triangle is famous because the largest area is there.
concentration of sharks
whites of the world.
NARRATOR: If the tides had swept the
fugitives to this sector,
the probability of
that they would survive would have decreased radically.
It is a reality of which
Red Triangle surfers are very aware.
It's October 2005 in Salmon
Creek, California, a popular surfing spot
north of the Golden Gate.
It's a beautiful autumn morning and Megan Halavais,
a 20-year-old girl,
arrives at the beach with a couple of friends.
Swim 150 meters and choose a place to stop and wait for the wave.
Sitting on her board, her instincts suddenly awaken.
MEGAN: I experienced a strange, ugly feeling.
Like a shiver down your spine.
I remember thinking, "I'd better go where the boys are."
NARRATOR: Suddenly, a gigantic jaw filled
with sharp teeth emerged
from the depths. It could be the end.
A great white shark feeding near the island
from Alcatraz revived the legend of Sharkatraz.
What would have happened if the fugitives had met?
with deadly sharks?
A horrific attack
meters from the coast could give us a terrifying clue.
October 2005 near San Francisco Bay.
MEGAN: I remember looking
over my shoulder and saw a gigantic fin behind me.
I saw a huge grey body and I saw bubbles in the water.
And then I just remember my hands pressing
against a gray flesh.
And the board and I were sucked underwater.
Everything disappeared. I was the board, the shark.
NARRATOR: The gigantic
Great white shark swam with Megan's board leash
hooked in the jaw.
MEGAN: I was determined to do what I came to do and
he just took me with him.
NARRATOR: The jaws of the
predator cut the plastic strap and that allowed Megan
return to the surface.
But will the shark return for another attack?
MEGAN: I clung to the first one
body I found and I didn't let go and I climbed on top of it.
They were yelling at me, "Come on, get on the board. Get on."
NARRATOR: The gigantic bite, which went from the
upper leg
up to the calf, injured the muscle up to the
bone and reached one centimeter
of an important artery.
Megan is lucky to be alive.
But that attack was not the only one.
Along the California coast, surfers often
be the victims of shark attacks.
Scientists warn against demonizing
to predators.
Based on all the
information collected on these violent encounters,
Scientists are convinced that
Great white sharks do not go out to hunt humans.
In fact, most bites are obvious cases.
from a confusion.
SCOTT: When they look up and see a surfer on his board,
They see a long, cylindrical body
with fins, which are our feet and hands.
We are equal to their prey.
They think we are a seal.
That's why they go up with
all the violence of an attack and they bite
and then they realize they made a bad decision
After having sunk your teeth in.
But they cause us very serious wounds.
When we get spit on, we say, "I was attacked by a shark. Oh my God.
Look how much blood." But they were wrong.
NARRATOR: Although we know that great white sharks do not hurt,
people on purpose.
BOY: A great white shark! WOMAN: Oh my God.
NARRATOR: The new sighting
of a white shark feeding in the bay
The question arises: could they have reached the coast?
Alcatraz escapees
without having been attacked by sharks?
The latest escape from Alcatraz could answer that question.
once and for all.
December 1962.
Just six months after Morris's great escape
and the Anglin brothers,
John Paul Scott thinks it's time for him to escape too.
GEORGE: A prisoner who has
A sentence of 20, 30, or 50 years or life reaches a point
that anything is better than confinement.
They are willing to try everything
even if it is almost suicide to escape from there.
NARRATOR: While working in a kitchen basement,
discover a window
that someone else has already started filing.
Scott decides he will finish the job.
Day after day he uses everything he can get his hands on, even a string.
covered in wax
for the floor and cleaning powder to finish cutting the area
of steel.
And when it's almost over
decides to call a partner.
MAN: I was cutting out a basement window in the kitchen.
I'll escape from this rock. I think you should come with me.
NARRATOR: He tells his partner Darl Lee Parker that he's going to escape.
at that moment. MAN: Come on.
NARRATOR: All those who
tried were caught or are presumed dead.
Will they be able to overcome the
adversities and will arrive safe and sound to freedom
Or will they be new victims of the deadly legend of Sharkatraz?
It was said that it could not happen
A great white shark fed near Alcatraz Island,
within the San Francisco Bay.
BOY: A great white shark. WOMAN: Oh my God.
NARRATOR: Now this new
sighting has everyone wondering what really happened
with the Alcatraz prisoners who disappeared.
Did they drown or is the legend of Sharkatraz true?
The last two Alcatraz escapees could finally be released.
reveal ourselves if we escape from the rock
swimming is a death sentence.
December 16, 1962.
26 years after the
first fugitives disappeared from the rock
a new team of prisoners
John Paul Scott and Darl Lee Parker are ready to swim
in waters infested with
sharks in order to achieve their freedom.
It is very unlikely that they will succeed.
No one is known to have
I suspect he escaped from the rock alive.
The guards shot and killed 6.
Those who reached the water
were caught or presumed to have drowned.
But just after 5:30 p.m. Scott and Parker
They manage to reach the rocky coast of the island.
Before diving,
They inflate latex gloves and place them in their shirts.
These rudimentary floats could prevent them from sinking.
But they will not protect them
from the icy waters or from the sharks.
But there's no turning back now.
Minutes later the Alcatraz guards discover the
escape and sound the alarm.
The ships leave
immediately in search of the escaped convicts.
100 meters from the island
in a small group of rocks
known as Little Alcatraz they find one of the men
desperately clinging for dear life.
It's Darl Lee Parker.
No sign of John Paul Scott.
Is it possible that he survived the dangerously
cold bay water
or ran into the sharks
that the guards always mentioned to the prisoners?
Finally they receive a call.
Scott is living on the coast of San Francisco.
Almost two hours after his
escape, two young people find him on the verge of fainting
clinging to the rocks of Fort Point, 5 kilometers away
of Alcatraz.
GEORGIA: He was lucky
that the current would carry him out.
If he had gone 15 or 20 meters to his right, he would have passed through
under the bridge
and that would have been the end of it.
BILL: He fell on the rocks. In
reality was the only thing that could save him from going into the ocean.
He was so exhausted that he fainted on them.
They caught him and took him back to Alcatraz.
But he swam. He could have done it.
NARRATOR: May John Paul
Scott's survival proves that a prisoner could cross the
swimming bay without encountering a man-eating shark.
This fact has been confirmed many times since then.
Hundreds of people swim
from Alcatraz to the coast of San Francisco every year.
SCOTT: Actually, the
The probability of a great white shark attacking you is very low.
Surely, until the day of
Today there are sharks that pass under those who swim
near Alcatraz and it doesn't happen
nothing because they are not prey for them.
NARRATOR: The scientists
They believe that it is highly unlikely that some of the fugitives
have encountered a great white shark in the bay.
So what happened to the prisoners who disappeared?
Many speculate that Cole and Roe drowned in the bay.
As for Morris and the Anglin brothers, some believe
who managed to achieve freedom.
BOY: It's a great white shark.
But it is very likely that no prisoner would have
tried to escape if there were
given the violent attack
shark attack that took place at Alcatraz Pier.
BILL: All the guards would have loved a
great white shark gave that show
in front of the convicts.
DOUGLAS: If great white sharks decide to go hunting for their
food to the San Francisco Bay,
They will find great loot.
There are large numbers of sea lions at Pier 39
and there is also an increase
in the seal population on the rocks surrounding the bay.
This area could become a good hunting ground
hunting for sharks.
Only time will tell if they will actually stop being visitors for
short periods
to become full-time residents.
(music)
NARRATOR: In the end, it would seem
that the stories that the guards told the prisoners
about sharks
that were in the bay were just tools to control it.
WOMAN: Oh. My God, oh.
NARRATOR: But the violent one
Shark attack near Alcatraz could change
things in the future could
relive the legend of a rock from which it is impossible to escape
which some call "Sharkatraz".